Grigoriy Ovchinnikov

Data Scientist

Georgia, Tbilisi

□ ogoje@protonmail.com in grigoriy-o-a679501b5/

Data Scientist with 4 years of data analysis and machine learning experience. Strong knowledge of classical, advanced ML algorithms, applying deep learning and statistics. Proficiency in working with ML frameworks and databases for business problem-solving.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, SQL

Machine learning: Scikit-learn, XGBoost, LightGBM, CatBoost, PyTorch, SciPy, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib,

Plotly, Seaborn, pulearn, shap, MLflow

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Cassandra, HBase

Version Control & Deploy & Infrastructure: Git, GitLab CI/CD, Docker(compose, swarm), Flask

GCP: Cloud Functions, Cloud Run, Cloud Storage, PubSub, VertexAI

Big data: Hadoop, Hive, Pyspark

Natural Language Processing: gensim, nltk, transformers

Web scraping: Scrapy, Puppeteer, lxml

Project management: Jira, Confluence, Trello

Other: EDA, Data cleaning, Visualization, Modelling, Propensity Modelling, Model interpretation, Natural

Language Processing, Statistics, Experimental design, Hypothesis testing, MVP

EXPERIENCE

Platforma November 2020 - Present

Data Scientist

Moscow, Russia

- Implemented state-of-the-art methods for a look-alike modeling task with positive unlabeled (PU) learning using PySpark and PyTorch with a significant uplift in offline and online metrics.
- Built an efficient, accurate and scalable ML solution for labeling clickstream data which increased accuracy and lower inference time on telecom data in more than hundreds of million devices using PySpark and Hadoop.
- Suggested and implemented an NLP-inspired(item2vec) approach for website representation learning based on clickstream data, giving several advantages over the previous approach.
- Pipeline stack: Python, Hadoop, Pyspark, Airflow, PyTorch.

S7 TechLab

October 2018 - October 2020

Junior Data Scientist

Moscow, Russia

- Conducted research and data analysis to address predictive maintenance task. Provided estimates of remaining useful life through supervised machine learning in the big data department.
- Developed ML models for improving accuracy of decision support system using cluster analysis and supervised multiclass classification.
- Scraping external data with Python, Building MVP with R Shiny, Python Flask-restx.
- Pipeline stack: Python, Airflow, PySpark, S3, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Cassandra, Kafka.

SIDE PROJECTS

CatchBlogger Z | Co-founder and developer of YouTube influence marketing platform.

06 2022

- Responsible for whole data management pipeline: extraction, transformation and loading.
- Pipeline stack: Python, Puppeteer, GCP: Cloud Functions, Cloud Scheduler, Cloud Storage

EDUCATION

National Research Nuclear University (MEPhI)

Master's degree in Applied Mathematics and Informatics (incomplete)

September 2018 – June 2020

Moscow, Russia

Volgograd State Technical University (VSTU)

Bachelor's degree in Informatics and Computer Engineering

September 2014 – June 2018

Volgograd, Russia

CERTIFICATIONS

- Google Cloud, Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals [November 2022]
- TensorFlow on Google Cloud [November 2022]
- Drawing conclusions from data, MIPT, Yandex [October 2020]

Languages

- English B2(Upper intermediate)
- Russian Native